<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo on Gabriel Lazcano</title><link>https://gabriellazcano.com/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in hugo on Gabriel Lazcano</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Â© 2021 Gabriel Lazcano</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabriellazcano.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How did I make my blog with Hugo and Github Pages?</title><link>https://gabriellazcano.com/blog/my-stack/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabriellazcano.com/blog/my-stack/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So I decided to go into blogging, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried using the common blogging sites but being layed back by the tools they gave me wasn&amp;rsquo;t appealing at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to be explaining the stack I use to run this site and the things I noticed in the process. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be updating this page as I&amp;rsquo;m extending my stack.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-stack">The stack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this project I used one of the best tools for Static Site Generation, &lt;code>Hugo&lt;/code>. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy fast and you can customize almost everything. I know Hugo isn&amp;rsquo;t the most famous but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely one the most reliable. For the time being, I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen much attention to the framework and I would like to start contributing to making it widespread.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="set-up">Set Up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For setting up your own blog there are two ways, using a theme or creating your own. I tried using a theme but in the end it wasn&amp;rsquo;t fulfilling my needs. I think that the full customization of the themes can be a 2 sided sword, as modifying really anything is extremely difficult. Even more some themes do not have enough documentation and you have to guess how everything works. I get that themes are convenient for starting your site and for people that don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the mess but I felt it as I was feeling before choosing Hugo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will, in another occasion, of how to set up a theme in Hugo as, as I mentioned before, is extremely convenient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can go through the steps of starting your own site, as I did, in the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/"> gohugo.io documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hosting">Hosting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the hosting I&amp;rsquo;m currently using Github Pages. I set it up using a Github Action that automatically builds my site in another branch of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="custom-domain">Custom domain&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about how configuring a custom domain, I thought it was really straightforward and it kinda is but I had a huge problem setting it up. You can see how I did it in &lt;a href="https://gabriellazcano.com/blog/how-custom-domain/">this other post&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap Up&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I hope you will find this blog post useful and keep it handy for a quick reference. If you want to learn more about Hugo, web development, tips &amp;amp; tricks, please consider checking my other posts ðŸ˜&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy Coding!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>